Codex Meme Merch turns one owner-supplied premise into an inspectable garment
preview, built with Codex and GPT-5.6.
The public demo is deliberately non-sellable.
From the catalog, I open Solward Index and inspect four customer-facing
views: catalog, front, back, and the four print panels.
Size choices and checkout are disabled.
The rights note records original abstract wordplay, with no official logos,
copied posts, usernames, likenesses, or protected product layouts.
Behind this surface, GPT-5.6 provides bounded judgment: trend selection on the
scheduled route, exactly three structured art directions, and critique of actual
renders. Deterministic code owns provenance, schemas, rights checks, exact dimensions, six-panel
composition, hashes, prepress, state transitions, and every release gate.
Judgment never becomes authority.
The owner route skips only discovery.
It keeps the same guarded studio as the weekly route, where
exactly thirty authorized posts can produce a recurring trend or a
truthful no-trend stop. The shared pipeline validates each recipe, composes front,
back, both sleeves, panel label, and inside label, then asks GPT-5.6
to review the rendered garment itself.
Every contract, threshold, and prompt is visible for inspection.
At the judged Preview commit, eleven products validate, one hundred thirty-three
of one hundred thirty-three tests pass, and twelve of twelve browser
checks pass locally and against the public deployment.
Solward's critic score is eighty-seven out of one hundred.
AI disclosure: GPT-5.6 produced structured trend and art-direction judgments and reviewed
rendered images. Codex image generation assisted the concept board.
Six print panels and exact text were composed deterministically.
This voice was synthesized with OpenAI gpt-audio-1.5.
No payment, provider sync, publication, or fulfillment action is shown.
One sentence becomes an inspectable garment system, without a hidden commerce
claim. Explore the public Preview.